Finding Aid for Leslie Bassett Papers, 1946-2005
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Leslie Bassett Papers 1946-2005
Bassett, Leslie, 1905-
0601 Aa 2
Leslie Bassett is a composer and professor of music at the University of Michigan. Bassett’s papers, consisting of correspondence, collected memorabilia, photographs, lectures, scrapbooks, and music, document his career as a composer and professor of music.
35 linear feet in 47 boxes and various sizes
5 oversize volumes
72.2 GB online
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Leslie Bassett (donor no. 9672 ) through Charles Reynolds, U-M Music Library in November 2005.
The collection is open to research.
The collection contains audio tapes from which digital copies have been made. Source tapes are for staff use only. Audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.
Digitization: The Library has undertaken the digitization of a number of sound recordings within this collection. The resulting audio files are available for playback only in the Bentley Library Reading Room. Links to item images and additional information are available within this finding aid. Original sound recordings are only available for staff use.
Leslie Bassett is a composer and professor of music at the University of Michigan. He was born in Hanford, California on January, 23, 1923 and was exposed to music when he first learned to play the piano as a child. In high school, he continued piano and also picked up the trombone. After a few semesters at Fresno State University, he served in World War II in the 13th Armored Division Band of the US Army as a trombonist, but also composed and arranged music.
He earned his Bachelor's degree from Fresno State University in 1947 and then received both his master's degree (1949) and his doctorate (1956) in music composition at the University of Michigan, studying under Ross Lee Finney. In 1950, he was a Fulbright Fellow, studying at the École Normale de Musique in Paris. Bassett began teaching at the University of Michigan in 1952, remaining there until he retired in 1991. While at the University of Michigan, he helped to found the Electronic Music Studio and also headed the Composition Department.
Bassett earned many prizes and awards for his composing and his teaching. Most notably, he won the Pulitzer Prize in Music for Variations for Orchestra in 1966 and in 1984 was named the Henry Russel Lecturer, "the highest honor to be awarded a senior faculty member and the first time that the lectureship had gone to a musician or artist." (Johnson, p.3).
He composed his music for a variety of different instruments and genres including music for orchestra, wind ensemble, chamber music, choral music, brass, solo voice, instrumental solos, organ, piano as well as electronic music.
The Leslie Bassett Papers consist of correspondence, collected memorabilia, photographs, lectures, scrapbooks, and musical compositions documenting his career as a composer and professor in the School of Music of the University of Michigan.
This collection contains the following series: Correspondence, Memorabilia, Topical Files, Photographs, Scrapbooks, Sound Recordings, and Compositions.
Subjects:
Bassett, Leslie, 1923-; Composers--United States.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. School of Music.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Bassett, Leslie, 1923-; Bassett, Anita Denniston.; Concerts--United States.; Composers.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Sound recordings.
- Correspondence 1958-2005
  The Correspondence series (1958-2005, 3.5 linear ft.) is arranged by date, correspondent (name of individual or organization), and topic. Researchers can find both personal correspondence from friends and family as well as professional correspondence detailing different aspects of Bassett's career including music recording and publishing, guest composing, commissions, and awards and fellowships.
  - Chronological
    - 1959-1988, 18 folders (Box 1)
    - 1988-2004, 9 folders (Box 2)
    - Undated (Box 2)
  - By correspondent
    - Individuals
      - Finney, Ross Lee 1963-1981 (Box 2)
      - Letters from former students 1975-1983 (Box 2)
      - Letters from other composers 1960-1983 (Box 2)
      - University of Michigan colleagues 1981-1998 (Box 2)
      - Valentino, Callegarin 1967-1984 (Box 2)
    - Organizations
      - Abingdon Press 1965-1981 (Box 2)
      - Alfred Publishing Company, Inc./Hinshaw Music, Inc. 1977-2001 (Box 2)
      - Alphonse Leduc/Robert King Music Sales 1959-2003 (Box 2)
      - American Composers Alliance (ACA) 1957-2003 (Box 2)
      - American Composers Alliance Library 1953-1962 (Box 2)
      - American Composers Orchestra (ACO) 1991 (Box 2)
      - American Society of University Composers (ASUC) 1967-1981 (Box 2)
      - Autograph Editions 1966-1977 (Box 2)
      - The Brass Press 1973-1980 (Box 2)
      - Broadcast Music, Inc. (BMI) 1972-2002 (Box 2)
      - C. F. Peters Corporation 1966-2005, 5 folders (Box 3)
      - The Church Hymnal Corporation 1977 (Box 3)
      - Composers Facsimile Edition 1958-1969 (Box 3)
      - Detroit Symphony Orchestra 1989-1996 (Box 3)
      - Galaxy Music Corporation 1960-1967, 1989-1999 (Box 3)
      - Guggenheim (John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation) 1972-1981, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - International Trombone Association 1973-1975 (Box 3)
      - League of Composers -- International Society for Contemporary Music (ISCM) 1979 (Box 3)
      - Library of Congress (commission) 1968-1972 (Box 3)
      - Lorimer Publications 1983-1985 (Box 3)
      - Ludwig Music 1998-1999 (Box 3)
      - Master Musicians Collective 1992-2000 (Box 3)
      - National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities (UM sabbatical leave) 1966-1967 (Box 3)
      - National Endowment for the Arts 1979-1980 (Box 3)
      - New World Records 1979, 1998 (Box 3)
      - Opus One/CRI/Chestnut Brass 1993-1997 (Box 3)
      - Philadelphia Orchestra 1973-1982, 1994 (Box 3)
      - Philharmusica Co. 1999 (Box 3)
      - Prentice-Hall 1966-1982 (Box 3)
      - Pulitzer Prizes 1998-1999 (Box 3)
      - Theodore Presser Co. (Merion Music) 1977-2000 (Box 3)
      - University Music Press 1961-1981 (Box 3)
      - Who's Who, circa 1980s (Box 3)
      - World Library Publications 1969-2005 (Box 3)
  - Topical
    - Baltimore recording 1978-1980 (Box 4)
    - Commissions 1975-2005, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Drawings, cards, and music mostly by Leslie Bassett to his family (Box 4)
    - Guest composer 1971-2003 (Box 4)
    - Orchestras (other) 1992-1999 (Box 4)
    - Orchestra performances 1977-1979 (Box 4)
    - Permissions (texts) 1972-1973, 1996 (Box 4)
    - Recordings (other) 1996-1998 (Box 4)
    - Stanley Professorship 1977 (Box 4)
- Memorabilia 1946-2004
  The Memorabilia series, (1946-2004, 1.5 linear ft.) contains Bassett's collected memorabilia, including articles and clippings as well as programs of music events and performances. Most of the collected programs are from performances at which he conducted or when his music was performed.
  - Articles and clippings, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Programs
    - 1946-1961, 1 volumes (Box 4)
    - 1962-1986, 21 folders (Box 5)
    - 1987-2004, 14 folders (Box 6)
    - Undated (Box 6)
  - Citations and announcement posters (Box 45)
    (oversize)
- Topical Files 1983-2004
  The Topical Files (1983-2004, 0.5 linear ft.) series includes interviews of Bassett, several of Bassett's lectures (including his speech as the Henry Russel Lecturer), and various program notes.
  - Interviews
    - Johnson 1983 (Box 6)
    - Tomassini 2003 (Box 6)
  - Lectures/speeches
    - General and miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Commencement address for the School of Music, "Great Art Thou, O Music!" 1991 (Box 6)
    - Electronic music lecture (Box 6)
    - Henry Russel Lecture, "The Shape of Content," 1984 (Box 6)
    - Michigan Orchestra Association on repertory October 13, 1989 (Box 6)
    - "Music in changing times," 1971 (Box 6)
    - Pi Kappa Lambda (Box 6)
    - University of Michigan Scientific Club, "American Music: some old, some new," 1987 (Box 6)
    - "What are the origins of a new piece of music?" 1967 (Box 6)
    - World Day of Prayer, First Baptist Church, Ann Arbor, "A talk on prayer," February 10, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Music
    - List of works (Box 6)
    - Program notes (Box 6)
  - Robert Lee Finney memorial service 1997 (Box 6)
  - Teaching materials
    - Fugue manual, 2 volumes (Box 6)
- Photographs, 1977-2003
  The Photographs (1977-2003, 0.5 linear ft.) document Bassett's personal and professional life, including many photos of family, friends and colleagues as well as photographs of composers, performances, and events.
  - Concerts, performances, and events
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, award recipients May 15, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Composers Concordance concert November 1996 (Box 7)
    - Contemporary Directions Ensemble (CDE) program April 12, 2003 (Box 7)
    - Detroit Symphony Orchestra
      - Date unknown (Box 7)
      - Premiere of "Thoughts that Sing, Breathe, and Burn," February 27-March 1, 1997 (Box 7)
    - Midland (Mich.) Symphony Orchestra, premiere of "Concerto for Two Pianos and Orchestra," April 30, 1977 (Box 7)
    - Mu Phi Epsilon, 100th year anniversary celebration August 2003 (Box 7)
    - Orchestral Hall February 6-9, 1992 [and?] Calif., December 1991 (Box 7)
  - People
    - Colleagues and friends (Box 7)
    - Composers (Box 7)
    - Family (Box 7)
    - Paul Yeon Lee, Wendoyln Olson, Gabriela Frank at the time of the recording of "Sounds Remembered" for Equilibrium Records 2002 (Box 7)
    - Portraits of Anita and Leslie Bassett (Box 7)
  - Personal (Box 7)
- Scrapbooks 1991 (Box 7)
  The Scrapbooks (1991, 0.5 linear ft.) were compiled for Bassett upon his retirement from the University of Michigan in 1991. The scrapbooks include photographs, cards, letters, programs, and clippings covering his career in music and his time at the University of Michigan.
  - Retirement from UM 1991, 2 volumes (Box 7)
- Sound Recordings
  The Sound Recordings consist of reel-to-reel tapes, cassette tapes, and phonograph discs of Bassett compositions. Some of the recordings are commercially produced; others are recordings of premiere and subsequent performances of his work. In addition, there are a few recordings of some of his public lectures, including his Russel lecture.
  [Digitized audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.]
  - Pierrot Songs, 1988 November 07, 1989 January 25, 1989 February 15, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-102-1]; mp3 file; (Pierrot Songs, copy of premieres and UM performance. Christine Schadeberg, soprano, New York New Music Ensemble, Robert Black, conductor, Los Angeles Museum, Bing Theater. Einue Buhne, Herbst, Lucy Shelton, soprano with Da Capo Chamber Players, Arnold Schoenberg Institute, University of Southern California.)
    - [Part 2], [0601-SR-102-2]; mp3 file; (Pierrot Songs, copy of premieres and UM performance. Performance by the Contemporary Directions Ensemble, University of Michigan in Rackham Auditorium. Laura Lamport, soprano, Richard Rosenberg.)
  - Fourth String Quartet; Premiere New World Quartet, 1980 March 26, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-103-1]; mp3 file; (Performance of Leslie Bassett's Fourth String Quartet, by the New World Quartet.)
  - Brass Quintet, 1989 March 27, 1989 May 13, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-106-1-1]; mp3 file; (Premiere performance in Philadelphia March 27, 1989. Chestnut Brass Company, First Presbyterian Church. Bruce Barrie, Thos. Cook, trumpets; Marian Hesse, horn; David Vining, trombone; Jay Krush, tuba.)
    - [Part 2], [0601-SR-106-1-2]; mp3 file; (Performance in Ann Arbor, MI May 13, 1989; Recording of a rehearsal with string instruments, at 11:12 switches to a performance with wind instruments and strings.)
  - Echoes from an Invisible World, Premiere, 1976 February 27,1976 February 28, 1976 March 2, 1976 April 22, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-108-1-1]; mp3 file; (Echoes from an Invisible World tape from premier performance by the Philadelphia Orchestra, Eugene Ormandy conducting; Academy of Music, Philadelphia. February 27 - 28 and March 2, 1976.)
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-108-1-2]; mp3 file; (Interview with Ed. Burroughs on WUOM on the Eleventh Hour April 22,1976; Interview - intermission commentary for Philadelphia Orchestra broadcast with George Diehl from WQRS Detroit. includes interludes of Echoes from an Invisible World.)
  - Easter Triptych, 1960 February 15, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-118-1]; mp3 file; (Originals at WUOM; Easter Triptych 1958: Friday, Saturday, Sunday. Harold Hough, tenor, UM Orchestra Personnel, Josef Blatt, conducting.)
  - Triform; 3 Studies in Electronic Sounds,, 1966 November 29, 1972 November 20, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 15 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-119-1]; mp3 file; (Triform; 15 IPS, 2 Tracks, stereo, master copy of performances; 3 studies in Electronic Sounds.)
  - Five Movements for Orchestra, To Music, 1962 July 05, 1962 June 20, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-120-1]; mp3 file; (Five Movements for Orchestra by RAI Symphony Orchestra of Rome. Massimo Freccia, conducting. July 5, 1962; To Music; Patty Thompson Gay and John Eaton, June 20, 1962)
  - Music for Saxophone and Piano, Nonet, Quartet for Trombones; Music for Sax and Piano, 1949 March 05, 1968 April 16, August 01, 1972 February 09, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-121-1]; mp3 file; (Music for Saxophone and Piano; Elizabeth Zinn, Daniel Durand, Tempe Arizona; August 1, 1968; Nonet; Ithaca College Ensemble, Gregg Smith, conducting; April 16, 1968. Quartet for Trombones; Paul Wallace, Leslie Bassett, Glenn Yarberry, Charleen Symmonds, Evanston Ill; March 5, 1949. Music for Sax and Piano Gary Gray & Irma Valleeillo, UCLA Composers Concerts, Los Angeles; February 9, 1972.)
    - [Part 2], [0601-SR-121-2]; mp3 file; (Music for Saxophone and Piano; Elizabeth Zinn, Daniel Durand, Tempe Arizona; August 1, 1968; Nonet; Ithaca College Ensemble, Gregg Smith, conducting; April 16, 1968. Quartet for Trombones; Paul Wallace, Leslie Bassett, Glenn Yarberry, Charleen Symmonds, Evanston Ill; March 5, 1949. Music for Sax and Piano Gary Gray & Irma Valleeillo, UCLA Composers Concerts, Los Angeles; February 9, 1972.)
  - A Program of Works by Leslie Bassett, Boston University, 1980 March 14, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-124-1]; mp3 file; (Boston University Wind Ensemble; Paul Gay, conductor. Wind Music; Quartet for Trombones; Nonet; Designs, Images and Textures; Sounds, Shapes and Symbols. Includes program from performance in box.)
    - [Part 2], [0601-SR-124-2]; mp3 file; (Boston University Wind Ensemble; Paul Gay, conductor. Wind Music; Quartet for Trombones; Nonet; Designs, Images and Textures; Sounds, Shapes and Symbols. Includes program from performance in box.)
  - Contemporary Music Symposium Concert - Drake University: Nonet; Elaborations; Time and Beyond; Forces, 1976 April 13, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-126-1]; mp3 file; (Nonet; Elaborations: Guy Wuellner, piano; Time and Beyond; Marion Hall, baritone, James Luke, clarinet, John Ehrlich, cello, Frank Wiens, piano; Forces, Wilfred Biel, violin, John Ehrlich, cello, George Katz, piano, Drake University Orchestra, John Canaria, conductor. Box includes program for event.)
    - [Part 2], [0601-SR-126-2]; mp3 file; (Nonet; Elaborations: Guy Wuellner, piano; Time and Beyond; Marion Hall, baritone, James Luke, clarinet, John Ehrlich, cello, Frank Wiens, piano; Forces, Wilfred Biel, violin, John Ehrlich, cello, George Katz, piano, Drake University Orchestra, John Canaria, conductor. Box includes program for event.)
  - Celebration in Praise of Earth, 1971 October 14, 1971 October 31, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-130-1-1]; mp3 file; (Performers are: Symphony Orchestra and College Chorus; Wayne Zarr, director, Charles Smith, narrator, George Poinar, conductor. In Conservatory Auditorium, Baldwin Wallace College, Berea, Ohio. )
    - [Part 2], [0601-SR-130-1-2]; mp3 file; (Premier performance of October 14, 1971, in Gymnasium for Founders Day, Baldwin Wallace College, Berea, Ohio. Box notes that this recording is of poor quality.)
  - Sextet for Piano and Strings edited tape of premiere, 1972 April 27, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-131-1]; mp3 file; (Sextet for Piano and Strings edited tape of premiere performed in Washington, D.C. by the Juilliard String Quartet. Performers are: Robert Mann, Earl Carlyss, Samuel Rhodes, Claus Adam, John Graham, viola, WIlliam Masselos, piano. Recorded at Coolidge Auditorium, Library of Congress.)
  - Colloquy, Elaborations, 1969 May 23, 1970 November 02, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-132-1]; mp3 file; (Colloquy, Fresno Philharmonic Orchestra, Thos. Griswold, conductor; Convention Center, Fresno, California. May 23, 1969; Elaborations, Wesley True, pianist, Warrensburg, Missouri, November 2, 1970.)
  - Colloquy; Music for Saxophone and Piano, 1971 January 22, 1971 November 03, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-133-1-1]; mp3 file; (Colloquy, University of Michigan Symphony Orchestra, Theo Alcantara, condcutor. Contemporary Music Fest, Hill Auditorium, Ann Arbor. November 3, 1971; Music for Saxophone and Piano; January 22, 1971 Max Plank, Elaine Jacobsen, Pease Auditorium, Eastern Michigan University, Ypsilanti, Michigan.)
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-133-1-2]; mp3 file; (Colloquy, University of Michigan Symphony Orchestra, Theo Alcantara, condcutor. Contemporary Music Fest, Hill Auditorium, Ann Arbor. November 3, 1971; Music for Saxophone and Piano; January 22, 1971 Max Plank, Elaine Jacobsen, Pease Auditorium, Eastern Michigan University, Ypsilanti, Michigan.)
  - The Shape of Content – Henry Russel Lecture, 1984 March 21, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-135-1]; mp3 file; (Leslie Bassett 1984 Henry Russel Lecture: The Shape of Content given at Rackham Amphitheater March 21, 1984)
  - Sextet for Flutes, Clarinets, and Strings, 1980 February 21, 1982 May 15, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-136-1-1]; mp3 file; (Sextet for Flutes, Clarinets, and Strings Contemporary Directions Ensemble University of Michigan February 21, 1980; Sextet for Flutes, Clarinets, and Strings Musica Nova of Grand Rapids May 15, 1982. Includes program from performance of the Sextet from February 23, 1980.)
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-136-1-2]; mp3 file; (Sextet for Flutes, Clarinets, and Strings Contemporary Directions Ensemble University of Michigan February 21, 1980; Sextet for Flutes, Clarinets, and Strings Musica Nova of Grand Rapids May 15, 1982. Includes program from performance of the Sextet from February 23, 1980. Recording seems to be the same composition as SR-1-1, but is out of sync and the instrumentation seems differently balanced.)
    - [Part 2], [0601-SR-136-2]; mp3 file; (Sextet for Flutes, Clarinets, and Strings Contemporary Directions Ensemble University of Michigan February 21, 1980; Sextet for Flutes, Clarinets, and Strings Musica Nova of Grand Rapids May 15, 1982. Includes program from performance of the Sextet from February 23, 1980.)
  - Variations for Orchestra Premiere, 1963 July 06, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-137-1]; mp3 file; (Variations for Orchestra Premiere by RAI Symphony Orchestra of Rome July 6, 1963. Ferruccio Scaglia, conductor, Foro Italico, Rome. Tape made by USIS at time of broadcast of August 17, 1963.)
  - Concerto Lirico for Trombone and Orchestra; Premiere, Movements 1 and 2, 1984 April 07, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-138-1]; mp3 file; (Movements 1 and 2 of Concerto Lirico performed by the Toledo Symphony at the Toledo Museum of Art April 6 and 7, 1984. H. Dennis Smith, trombone, Yuval Zaliouk, conductor. Begins with radio announcer's commentary. )
  - Concerto Lirico for Trombone and Orchestra; Premiere, Movements 3 and 4, 1984 April 07, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-139-1]; mp3 file; (Movements 3 and 4 of Concerto Lirico performed by the Toledo Symphony at the Toledo Museum of Art April 6 and 7, 1984. Includes preliminary and after-performance remarks by the FM91 Toledo announcer.)
  - Lord, Who Hast Formed Me; Sing to the Lord; Whoe’er She Be; Lord, Who Hast Formed Me, 1982 March 14, 1987 April 4, 1988 October 21, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-141-1]; mp3 file; (October 21, 1988: Lord, Who Hast Formed Me - UM Chamber Choir; Sing to the Lord - UM Chamber Choir. Conducted by Theo Morrison, organ by Karl Schrock. April 4, 1987: Whoe’er She Be - UM Women's Glee Club. Rosalie Edwards conducting, Gary Adler, Piano. March 14, 1982: Lord, Who Hast Formed Me -First United Methodist Church Chancel Choir Emily Lowe, conductor, Mary Stubbins, organ.)
  - Illuminations, 1990 March, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 15 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-142-1]; mp3 file; (Leslie Bassett's Illuminations, Keith Bryan; flute, Karen Kays, piano. Includes engineer's take sheet.)
  - From a Source Evolving, 1986 November 01,1988 November 18, 1988 November 19, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-143-1]; mp3 file; (From a Source Evolving: Grand Rapids Symphony Orchestra November 18 and 19 1988. Catherine Comet, conducting. From cassette supplied by WUOM.)
    - [Part 2], [0601-SR-143-2]; mp3 file; (Premier performance by Midland Symphony Orchestra, conducted by Neal Gittlemen November 1, 1986; University of Michigan Philarmonia, Leo Najar conducting, November 24, 1986.)
  - Soliloquies, 1983?, 1987 November 14, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-144-1-1]; mp3 file; (Soliloquies, Clarinet solo. Performer listed is Fred Ormand as November 14, 1987.)
    - [Part 2], [0601-SR-144-1-2]; mp3 file; (Soliloquies performed by Yoshinori Nakao date on box purports this recording is from 1983.)
  - Liturgies, 1980 February 25, 1980 October 20, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-149-1]; mp3 file; (Liturgies: Marilyn Mason, premiere performance at the 21st Annual Conference on Organ Music at University of Michigan, October 20, 1980. John Peterson, New Music Festival IX Memphis State University February 25, 1982.)
  - Concerto for Two Pianos and Orchestra Premiere, 1977 April 30, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-150-1]; mp3 file; (Concerto for Two Pianos and Orchestra Premiere April 30, 1977 commissioned and performed by the Midland Symphony Orchestra with guest artists Nelita True and Fernando Laires. Don. Th. Jaeger, conductor.)
    - [Part 2 ], [0601-SR-150-2]; mp3 file; (Concerto for Two Pianos and Orchestra Premiere April 30, 1977 commissioned and performed by the Midland Symphony Orchestra with guest artists Nelita True and Fernando Laires. Don. Th. Jaeger, conductor.)
  - A Ring of Emeralds, Notes in the Silence, 1967 January 22, 1982 March 10, 1985 November 25, Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
    - [Part 1], [0601-SR-152-1-1]; mp3 file; (A Ring of Emeralds University of Michigan Choir conducted by Patrick Gardner,March 10, 1982.)